

Frank Gaete

frank.gaete1@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/frankgaete/

https://frankgaete1.github.io/portfolio/

Summary

With over 25 years as a UI/UX designer, I feel extremely fortunate in how much I continue to enjoy what I do. Throughout that time I've worked in numerous verticals and organizations ranging from small startups to fortune 500 companies gaining additional experience including UX research, front end coding, project/team leading and more along the way.

Work Experience

TD Bank, Sr. UX Designer

Aug 2021 – present, Remote

- Design interfaces and experiences for client facing products and services
- Develop wireframes, visual designs, user flows/journeys using Figma, Adobe XD
- Plan and design UX research goals and prototypes; analyze data to guide design enhancements Collaborate with pod members (PO, scrum master, devs, QA, content and others); cross team
- members and enterprise UX designers to ensure consistency across products and platforms

NextEra/Florida Power & Light, Sr. UX Design & Research

Jan 2020 – Jul 2021, Jupiter FL

- Designed interfaces and experiences for nuclear power enterprise applications
- Planned and executed UX research; analyze data to guide design enhancement recommendations; help standardize UX research methods and processes for future testing
- Developed new design patterns and workflows using Adobe XD, Sketch, and UXpin
- Collaborated with nuclear team members; product owners and enterprise UX designers

Clever Devices, Sr. UX Architect

Sep 2017 – Dec 2019, Woodbury NY

- Designed interfaces and experiences across several major product groups for desktop, responsive and mobile applications as per requirements, business goals and user research
- Promoted the value of UX research; defined and executed research processes and methodologies to drive design enhancement recommendations
- Designed and defined pattern libraries, style guides, UI/UX policies; software and hardware recommendations
- Collaborated with various teams to ensure consistency across products and corporate communications

Valiant Solutions, UX Director

Jul 2016 – Feb 2017, Woodbury NY

- Provided UI/UX design for entire SaaS platform across desktop and mobile devices
- Led ideation sessions with executives, dev leads, business analysts, art director, project manager; conceptualized design ideas via wireframes, workflows, mockups and HTML/CSS prototypes
- Worked with Creative Director and other Marketing team members to ensure alignment across web apps and corporate communications; redesigned corporate site using WordPress
- Created, maintained and socialized UI/UX policies including design; HTML/CSS coding; responsive web design; HTML email; accessibility standards; continuous improvement and more Led UX research including usability tests, surveys; analyzed usage metrics; set goals; organized
- and communicated results/feedback; documented UI/UX enhancement recommendations

Education

B.A. Social Science

Adelphi University, Garden City

Certificate

Internet Architecture at Hofstra University, Uniondale

Certificate

Client Server Systems at Dowling College, Oakdale

Skills

UI/UX Design
PC/Mac
Adobe XD, Creative Suite
Figma
UX Research
HTML, CSS
Ideation, collaboration

Military Experience

Agile, Jira

US Army Reserve. Highest Rank: Sergeant. Honorable Discharge

Interests

Tennis
Guitar
Movies, music
Travel
Boating
Family & friends



Frank Gaete

- frank.gaete1@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/frankgaete/
 - https://frankgaete1.github.io/portfolio/

Work Experience (continued)

Broadridge Financial Solutions, Lead UI/UX Architect

Apr 2011 – Jul 2016, Edgewood NY

- Converted business requirements and user research into sketches, wireframes, high fidelity mockups and HTML-CSS-jQuery prototypes for multiple projects
- Created, maintained and communicated UI/UX policies including design; design/development approaches; supported browsers; responsive web design; HTML email; accessibility standards
- Provided creative direction and technical UI/UX guidance for desktop and mobile, application platforms
- Worked with financial application teams including tax, transfer agency, shareholder, banks, brokers, shared data services, corporate governance, proxy voting, mutual funds, universal edelivery
- Collaborated with executives; product managers; developers; BAs and other stakeholders to successfully meet UI/UX requirements

Experience 2009 - 1997

- CA Technologies Web Developer, Islandia NY
- The Creative Group Web Designer/Developer, Rockville Center NY
- Veritas Laboratories Senior Designer / Developer / Project Manager, Bohemia NY
- **Dowling College**: Web Services Administrator, Oakdale NY
- theglobe.com Web Producer/Developer, Manhattan NY
- Channel21 Productions Webmaster/Technical Manager, Miller Place NY

References

Available upon request

Education

B.A. Social Science

Adelphi University, Garden City

Certificate

Internet Architecture at Hofstra University, Uniondale

Certificate

Client Server Systems at Dowling College, Oakdale

Skills

UI/UX Design
PC/Mac
Adobe XD, Creative Suite
Figma
UX Research
HTML, CSS

Ideation, collaboration Agile, Jira

Military Experience

US Army Reserve. Highest Rank: Sergeant. Honorable Discharge

Interests

Tennis Guitar

Movies, music

Travel

Boating

Family & friends